Some search for battle, others are born into it...
One Battle After Another is a thriller, crime, action
film directed by Paul Thomas Anderson.
Washed-up revolutionary Bob exists in a state of stoned paranoia, surviving
off-grid with his spirited, self-reliant daughter, Willa.
When his evil nemesis resurfaces after 16 years and she goes missing, the former radical
scrambles to find her, father and daughter both battling the consequences of his past.
Bob, played by Leonardo DiCaprio.
Col. Steven J. Lockjaw, played by Sean Penn.
Willa, played by Chase Infiniti.
Sensei Sergio St. Carlos, played by Benicio del Toro.
Deandra, played by Regina Hall.
Perfidia, played by Teyana Taylor.
One Battle After Another is a 2025 American black comedy action-thriller
film produced, written, and directed by Paul Thomas Anderson.
It is inspired by the 1990 novel Vineland by Thomas Pynchon.
The film's ensemble cast is led by Leonardo DiCaprio, Sean Penn, Benicio del Toro,
Regina Hall, Teyana Taylor, and Chase Infiniti (in her film debut).
The story follows an ex-revolutionary who is forced back into his former combative
lifestyle when he and his daughter are pursued by a corrupt military officer.
Anderson had wanted to adapt Vineland since the early 2000s and, eventually,
incorporated his own stories into the narrative while writing the screenplay.
The film was shot in California between January and June 2024 using VistaVision, becoming one of
the first films to use this format for principal photography since the 1960s.
One Battle After Another had its premiere at the TCL Chinese Theatre in Los Angeles,
California, on September 8, 2025, and was released in the United States by Warner Bros.
Pictures on September 26.
The film received critical acclaim.
The most expensive film of Anderson's career, it became his highest-grossing film, though it
underperformed at the box office, grossing $208 million on a $130–175 million budget.
One Battle After Another was nominated for nine awards at the 83rd Golden Globe Awards, receiving the most
nominations of any film that year, winning four, including Best Motion Picture – Musical or Comedy.
It also made history at the 32nd Actor Awards by receiving seven nominations (the most for any film in the awards' history),
including Outstanding Performance by a Cast in a Motion Picture, and at least one nomination in all other film categories.
At the 98th Academy Awards, it received the second-most nominations with thirteen, including
Best Picture, Best Director, Best Adapted Screenplay and four acting nominations.
The film explores themes of rebellion, based on novel or
book, resistance, usa–mexico border, riot.
The tone is intense.